<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on KuduLab</title>
    <link>https://kudulab.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on KuduLab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kudulab.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Terraform vs AWS CloudFormation vs AWS CDK</title>
      <link>https://kudulab.io/posts/2023-2-terraform-vs-cdk-vs-cloudformation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kudulab.io/posts/2023-2-terraform-vs-cdk-vs-cloudformation/</guid>
      <description>As Wikipedia explains:
 Infrastructure as code (IaC) is the process of managing and provisioning computer data centers through machine-readable definition files, rather than physical hardware configuration or interactive configuration tools.
 IaC is one of the DevSecOps practices. With IaC you can manage your infrastructure (bare metal, virtual machines, containers, databases, networking services and other resources) in a similar way as you would manage the code of any other project (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terraform license updated to Business Source License (BSL)</title>
      <link>https://kudulab.io/posts/2023-1-terraform-license-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kudulab.io/posts/2023-1-terraform-license-change/</guid>
      <description>You may have noticed the recent changes around Terraform licensing. This post explains the current situation and who is affected.
The one-git-commit change It all started with this git commit on 11th August 2023.
This commit changed the license of Terraform from MPL (Mozilla Public License) to BSL (Business Source License). What does it mean?
The consequences There are many consequences of that license change. Some Terraform users will not be affected:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colima, Dojo and the end of Docker Desktop</title>
      <link>https://kudulab.io/posts/2022-dojo-colima/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kudulab.io/posts/2022-dojo-colima/</guid>
      <description>We wrote this post because of the recent update to the Docker Desktop licensing. Dojo, a CLI tool that we wrote, uses Docker and Docker-Compose. As many organisations are moving away from Docker Desktop, we&amp;rsquo;d like to help you continue using Dojo while staying compliant with the licenses. The proposed solution focuses on Colima.
Are license updates applicable to you? First, if you use Docker on Linux, this situation does not concern you (see: source).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting AWS SysOps Administrator certified</title>
      <link>https://kudulab.io/posts/aws-sysops-exam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kudulab.io/posts/aws-sysops-exam/</guid>
      <description>In July 2019, I&amp;rsquo;ve passed the AWS Certified SysOps Administrator - Associate. I decided to share my experiences leading to it, because while there is a lot of resources for learning AWS, choosing the time-efficient ones requires some extra effort. While I am not an expert in AWS (with just one certificate), my learning path was quite smooth. I learned a lot in a short time, then passed the exam with a high score of 973/1000, which is what many people could aim for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EC2 instance with Terraform and Ansible</title>
      <link>https://kudulab.io/posts/3-ec2-ansible-dojo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kudulab.io/posts/3-ec2-ansible-dojo/</guid>
      <description>In this post we explain how to deploy an AWS EC2 instance using Terraform and then provision it using Ansible. Those tasks will be performed in multiple Dojo docker images.
The supporting code may be found on github. All the tools used are open source. The setup was tested on Ubuntu 18.04 LTS.
Audience You will be interested in this post if you:
 want to learn how to deploy EC2 instances with Terraform want to make your deployments from Docker, using Dojo want to know how to provision a Virtual Machine using Ansible and SSH  Requirement The requirement here is to:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GoCD configuration validation with preflight API</title>
      <link>https://kudulab.io/posts/gocd-preflight-validation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kudulab.io/posts/gocd-preflight-validation/</guid>
      <description>In GoCD 19.2.0 preflight API endpoint was merged, which allows to validate local GoCD configuration files (e.g. YAML, JSON) before submitting them to source control.
Every user has been long annoyed by slow feedback, when pushing configuration changes to GoCD only to find out in a moment that something is wrong on the errors and warnings page. This required to ammend last commit or push another one.
With the new API and gocd-cli it is now possible to get the same feedback before pushing changes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo blog on gh-pages with terraform and AWS Route 53</title>
      <link>https://kudulab.io/posts/blog-aws-github-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kudulab.io/posts/blog-aws-github-pages/</guid>
      <description>This is a self-referential post about deploying a personal blog on github pages. It describes how kudulab.io is deployed, starting from scratch, ending with fully-working website deployed using best practices.
All of the supporting code is hosted on github, just like all the open source tools used.
Audience This post will be most useful to someone building a personal website with similar technologies. You may still find some pieces useful if you</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>